Samuel Cristobal, Software Engineer

Contact

Email: el.tobal@gmail.com

• Phone: +34 646 49 09 06

Address: Calle Frontera, 10. 28240 Madrid, Spain

Links:

Github: github.com/scristobal

• Npm: npmjs.com/~samuelsh

Linkein: linkedin.com/in/scristobal

• Twitter: twitter.com/TypeSamuel

Summary

In 2019, I co-founded DataBeacon and assumed the role of CTO. Since then, I have been working as a full-stack Software Engineer, writing mostly TypeScript, React, Go and Node.

The company has grown to around ~20 employees, so it is time for me to move on and find new challenges possibly as an IC.

Previously, I worked 7+ years as a Research Engineer, in data mining and network optimization with Python and C. I have a MSc. + BSc. with honours in Mathematics -majored in algebraic geometry and logic- and B.Eng. in Telecommunication systems, best record award 2005.

Skills

- Programming languages: TypeScript, React, Go, Node, Python, Scala and C.
- Technologies: Next, tRPC, REST, WebSockets, Kafka, Redux, RKT, React Query, SWR, Zod, RxJS, SocketIO, MapboxGL, Turf, Recharts, sass, styled-components, Jest, Testing Library, Webpack, Nodejs, Express, Prisma, Postgres, KafkaJS, NextAuth, AuthO, jwt, gorilla/websocket, kafka-go, go-net/http, azure-go-sdk
- Languages: English and Spanish

Experience

Sofware Engineer

DataBeacon (www.databeacon.aero).

From January 2019 until present day.

Responsabilities:

- In charge of building all user-facing applications and backend services.
 - Build single page applications (SPAs) using TypeScript and React-Redux-Nextjs.

- Develop REST APIs and WebSockets back-end services in either Nodejs or Go.
- Contribute to basic CI/CD pipelines using Azure DevOps.
- Help define UX and contributed to the UI design system using Figma and Storybook.
- Responsible for building a team of software engineers, data engineers and data scientists.
 - Establish best practices, workflows, tooling, linting, testing, pipelines and code style.
 - Engenieering team management and coordination.
 - Support data engineering and machine learning teams with Python and Scala-Spark on DataBricks.

Research Engineer

Innaxis R&D (www.innaxis.org).

From October 2011 until December 2018.

Responsabilities:

- Responsible for data science and artificial intelligence research, solutions and platforms.
 - Write scientific software using Python, C and Matlab-Simulink in the field of network optimization, data mining and knowledge discovery.
 - Deploy, test and profile Machine Learning models on AWS using custom scripts on EC2.
- Became Senior Research Engineer in December 2013 and Technical Director in June 2017.
 - Principal investigator for data science international research projects.
 - Scientific and technical writing, publications and conferences.

Associate Research Fellow

Universität Wien.

From October 2010 until September 2011.

Field: Algebraic geometry: finding intricated, singular geometries over finite fields with C.

Assistant Intern

Universidad Autonoma de Madrid.

From October 2009 until September 2010

Field: Mathematical logic: model theory of formal systems with PROLOG.

Education

- MSc Mathematics and applications. Graduated in 2010. Major: algebra and logic. School: Universidad Autonoma de Madrid.
- BSc with honors in Mathematics. Major: algebra and logic. Graduated in 2009. School: Universidad Complutense de Madrid.
- BEng Telecomunications. Thesis: "Pseudo-random number generators based on discrete, chaotic attractors" with C. Graduated in 2005. School: Universidad Politecnica de Madrid.